Greedy algorithms, a greedy algorithm is an approach for solving a problem by selecting the best option
available at the moment.
It does not worry whether the current best result will bring the overall optimal result.
The algorithm never reverses the earlier decision, even if the choice is wrong.
It works in a top down approach.
This algorithm may not produce the best result for all the problems.
It's because it always goes for the local best choice to produce the global best result.
However, we can determine if that algorithm can be used with any problem.
If the problem has the following properties so how that greedy algorithm usage we use their greedy algorithm
in two cases their greedy choice property.
If an optimal solution to be to the problem can be found by choosing the best choice at each step without
reconsidering the previous steps one to choose, then the problem can be solved using a grid.
The approach the property is called greedy choice property.
The second case that we use the greedy algorithm is by using up to optimal substructure if the optimal
overall solution to the problem corresponds to the optimal solution of its sub problems.
Then the problem can be solved using equity approach.
This property is called optimal substructure.
For example.
You have to make a change of an amount using of the smallest using the smallest possible numbers of
coins amount equal $18.
The available coins are $5 coin, $2 coin and $1 coin.
For this example, there is no limit to the number of each coin you can use.
So we need to make $18 when that from the coins that are available and we need to make the smallest
possible number of coins five to one.
So how to do that?
We start by creating an empty solution minus set available coins are five, two and one.
We are supposed to find this sum equal to 18, starting from some equal to zero.
And we always select the coin with the largest value, which in this example is equal to five until
the sum is greater than 18.
When we select the largest value at each step, we hope to reach the destination faster.
The concept is called liquidity of choice property because we need the optimal solution.
In the first iteration solution minus set five.
In sum, equal to five.
The second iteration solution set five five and the sum equal to 10, third iteration 15 and the fourth
iteration.
We have 20, so 20 is greater than 18, so we removed five.
So we have now 35.
We add another coin that it is less than five.
Which is.
So five, five, five and two now some equals 270.
We cannot select five here because if we do with the sum is equal to 20, which is greater than 18.
So the second largest item, which is do I select similarly in the fifth iteration, select one.
And now the sum is equal to 18 and the solution is the solution set is five, five, five and two do.
This is that greedy algorithm.
Let's learn about the types of grid, the algorithm we have selection Earth that we have learned about
it in the previous videos.
That knapsack problem, we will see it the minimum spanning tree, the single source, shortest path
problem, SSP job scheduling problem frames, minimal, minimal spanning tree problems, cruise code,
minimum spanning tree broadband, Robin and Dijkstra minimal spanning tree algorithm Huffmon Coding
and Ford Focus on algorithm.
We will see this algorithm in and algorithms in the next videos, so I hope you are ready for this.